#### Contact

(727) 480-9735 (Mobile) ixchel10@msn.com

www.linkedin.com/in/evelyncotto (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

**Critical Care** 

**BLS** 

Nursing

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Basic Life Support (BLS)

Certification for Adult Critical Care Nurses (CCRN)

Registered Nurse, State of Florida Advanced Cardiovascular Life

Support (ACLS)

# Evelyn Cotto, BSN, RN, CCRN

Clinician at Tampa General Hospital

Brandon, Florida

## Summary

I'm a registered nurse licensed to work in Florida and California. In my 24 years of experience as an RN, I have worked as a clinician, cardiovascular nurse and educator. I love bedside nursing, and have been doing critical care for about 19 years.

I received my bachelors degree in nursing with honors from the University of Puerto Rico, Medical Science Campus.

# Experience

Tampa General Hospital Clinician June 2020 - Present (1 month)

HealthTrust Workforce Solutions Per diem RN February 2020 - June 2020 (5 months)

FlexCare Medical Staffing Travel Registered Nurse February 2018 - January 2020 (2 years) California

Tampa General Hospital Clinical Nurse January 2003 - January 2018 (15 years 1 month) Tampa, FL

Staff nurse, CTICU and Vascular ICU

Offer care for critically ill patients after cardiovascular surgery, including CABG, valve repairs and replacements, CEA, vascular bypass, AAA endovascular and open repairs, lung and heart transplants and insertion of VAD or ECMO. Super user for CRRT and EPIC EMR system. Clinician from 2010 to 2012 in charge of performance improvement data collection, peer audits, discipline and scheduling employees.

Memphis VA Medical Center Clinical Nurse 2000 - 2002 (2 years) Memphis, TN

Staff nurse, Surgical Intensive Care Unit

Provided care for critically ill patients before and after surgical procedures, such as neck resection, CEA, esophagectomy, thoracotomy, CABG, bowel resection, and vascular bypass surgery. Nurse in charge responsibilities on the night tour.

Cardiovascular Center of Puerto Rico and the Caribbean Clinical Nurse-Educator 1996 - 2000 (4 years) San Juan, Puerto Rico

Staff nurse and educator, surgical step-down unit.

Managed care for post cardiothoracic surgery patients in a telemetry stepdown unit. Preceptor for new staff and coordinated monthly educational meetings for employees, patients and family.

## Education

University of Puerto Rico, Medical Science Campus Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1992 - 1996)